<div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://hl7.org/fhir ../../src-generated/schemas/fhir-single.xsd" lang="en">
    <p>
        The following are key personas that play a critical role in COVID-19 reporting. Their roles and responsibilities ensure that COVID-related data is accurate and complete. By collaborating and communicating effectively, they help to improve the quality of COVID reporting and contribute to a more effective public health response.
    </p>

    <ul>
        <li>
            <strong>Healthcare providers</strong> involved in the collection of COVID data which include COVID testing, treatment, and care. These personas are responsible for ensuring that COVID data is accurate and complete.
        </li>

        <li>
            <strong>Public health / Surveillance officers</strong> who use the COVID data to track the spread of the virus and to develop public health strategies. They may access the data through a public health reporting system.
        </li>

         <li>
            <strong>Laboratory personnels</strong> who perform COVID testing and generate test results. They may be responsible for transmitting the test results to healthcare providers or public health / Surveillance officers.
        </li>

         <li>
            <strong>Clients</strong> are the individuals who are tested for COVID or receive treatment for the virus. 
        </li>

         <li>
            <strong>Health information technology (IT) professionals</strong> are the professionals who design, develop, and maintain the systems and tools used to collect, store, and transmit COVID-related data. They are responsible for ensuring the security and privacy of the data.
        </li>

         <li>
            <strong>Business analysts</strong> also play an instrumental role in COVID reporting. They help ensure that the technical systems and tools used to collect and report COVID-related data meet the needs of all stakeholders. Overall, Business analysts help to bridge the gap between technical requirements and stakeholder needs. By collaborating with various stakeholders, Business analysts help to ensure that the technical systems and tools used for COVID reporting are effective, efficient, and meet the needs of all parties involved. Some specific roles and responsibilities of Business analysts in the COVID reporting include:
            <ol>
                <li>
                    Analyzing data requirements. Working closely with the key stakeholders such as healthcare providers, public health &amp; surveillance officials, and laboratory staff, Business analysts help to identify the data elements needed for collection and reporting in relation to COVID-19. They use this information to develop data dictionaries to guide the technical implementation.
                </li>

                <li>
                    Identifying reporting workflows: In collaboration with other stakeholders, Business analysts help in developing COVID reporting workflows. This includes how data is collected, transmitted, and analyzed. These workflows and information aid development of process maps and other documentation needed to guide the technical implementation.
                </li>

                <li>
                    Evaluating technical solutions: Business analysts also collaborate with health IT professionals to evaluate different technical solutions for COVID data collection and reporting, such as health information exchange platforms, data warehouses, or reporting portals. They provide inputs on how well these solutions meet the needs of stakeholders. 
                </li>

                <li>
                    Testing and validation: Business analysts work with health IT professionals to ensure that the technical systems and tools used for COVID reporting are working correctly. Their role is to help design and execute test cases, identify and resolve technical issues, and ensure that the data being collected and reported is accurate and complete.
                </li>
            </ol>
        </li>
    </ul>
</div>