<div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://hl7.org/fhir ../../src-generated/schemas/fhir-single.xsd" lang="en">
    <style>
    {% include custom.css %}
  </style>

    <h3>Overview</h3> <a name="usecase-description"> </a>

    <p>
        The following uses cases have been identified for this implementation guide.
    </p>

    <p class="heading">Use Case Diagram</p>
    <p></p>
    
    <figure>
        {% include UseCaseDiagram.svg %}
        <figcaption>Use Case Diagram</figcaption>
    </figure>

   <p class="heading">Use Case Context</p>

    <p>
        This use case supports integration between the EMR and lab systems in order to effectively process lab requests and have the results returned to the EMR for diagnosis.
        <br />
        <br />
        In addition, this use case illustrates the need for a Centralised Data Repository (DR) and a Client Registry (CR) to enable regional and/or national COVID19 case reporting. 
        <br />
        <br />
        The <a href="index.html#technicalBackground">technical specificaton documentation</a> for the Data Integration Strategy &amp; Implementation reference platform identifies the following technologies for the two aforementioned centralised repositories.
    </p>
    <ol>
        <li><strong>DR:</strong> <a href="https://hapifhir.io/hapi-fhir/docs/getting_started/introduction.html" target="_blank">HAPI FHIR</a></li>
        <li><strong>CR:</strong> <a href="https://jembi.gitbook.io/jembi-platform/packages/client-registry-santempi" target="_blank">SanteMPI</a></li>
    </ol>

    <blockquote class="stu-note">
        <ul>
            <li>This use case diagram is limited to the <a href="bundles.html">specification</a> for this implementation guide and will not discuss the architectural componenets for the DR, CR and Data Mart.</li>
            <li>For more information regarding the implementation of a the architectural componenets, please see the <a href="index.html#technicalBackground">technical specificaton documentation</a>.</li>
        </ul>
    </blockquote>

    <h3>Use Case Summary</h3> <a name="usecase-summary"> </a>
    <p class="heading">Register Client</p>

    <p>Before an individual can be screened and assessed (diagnosis) for COVID19, the individual must be registered into the EMR at the assessing facility/organisation.</p>

    <p class="heading">Assess Client</p>
    <p>
        A nurse must be able to restrospectively capture existing screening and assessment data for individuals who 
        are continuing with their <a href="vaccination_status.html#vaccine-series">vaccination series</a> at a different facility where it is a 
        first-time visit or if the visited facility has older data in regards to the progression towards being <a href="vaccination_status.html#up-to-date-vaccinated">up-to-date vaccinated</a> for COVID19.
        <br />
        <br />
        In addition, this use case enables the nurse to capture the following key data.
    </p>

    <ul>
        <li>Metadata</li>
        <li>Presentation information (Asymptomatic, Symptomatic)</li>
        <li>Presenting symptoms and any pre-existing conditions and/or comorbidities</li>
        <li>History of hospitalisation for COVID19</li>
        <li>The COVID19 diagnosis taken from the most recent lab examination</li>
        <li>Treatment needs</li>
    </ul>

    <p class="heading">Document Client Outcome</p>

    <p>
        An individual who has been diagnosed positive for COVID19, typically, has one of the following outcomes.
    </p>

    <ul>
        <li>Recovered (symptoms resolved)</li>
            <ul>
                <li>Those individuals who previosly suffered from the disease are no longer shpwing any symptoms.</li>
            </ul>
        <li>Long COVID / Post-COVID</li>
            <ul>
                <li>Those individuals who suffer long-term affects which could range anywhere between a few weeks to even years <a href="#ref1">(Post-COVID Conditions, 2022)</a>.</li>
            </ul>
        <li>Death</li>
            <ul>
                <li>Those individuals who have suffered death due to exposure to COVID19.</li>
            </ul>
    </ul>

    <p class="heading">Submit lab order</p>

    <p>
        A nurse must be able to submit a request from the EMR for a sample to be collected and examined at the laboratory. 
        <br />
        <br />

        A lab request, in the context of this implementation guide, will typically contain the following key data. 
    </p>

     <ul>
        <li>Metadata</li>
        <li>Order number</li>
        <li>Test requested code</li>
            <ul>
                <li><strong>SARS-CoV-2 (COVID-19) Ag [Presence] in Respiratory specimen by Rapid immunoassay:</strong> <a href="https://loinc.org/94558-4/" target="_blank">94558-4</a></li>
                <li><strong>SARS-CoV-2 (COVID-19) RNA [Cycle Threshold #] in Respiratory specimen by NAA with probe detection:</strong> <a href="https://loinc.org/94745-7/" target="_blank">94745-7</a></li>
            </ul>
        <li>Reason for the test</li>
        <li>Specimen type</li>
            <ul>
                <li id="specimen-type-nasopharyngeal"><strong>Nasopharyngeal:</strong> <a href="https://www.findacode.com/snomed/258500001--nasopharyngeal-swab.html?hl=258500001" target="_blank">258500001</a></li>
                <li id="specimen-type-oropharyngeal-swab"><strong>Oropharyngeal swab:</strong> <a href="https://www.findacode.com/snomed/461911000124106--oropharyngeal-swab.html" target="_blank">461911000124106</a></li>
                <li id="specimen-type-unknown"><strong>Unknown:</strong> <a href="https://www.findacode.com/snomed/119324002--specimen-of-unknown-material.html" target="_blank">119324002</a></li>
            </ul>
        <li>Specimen ID</li>
    </ul>

    <p class="heading">Sample Collection</p>

    <p>
        A lab assistant must be able to collect samples that have been submitted for testing from the EMR.
        <br />
        <br />

        Sample collection in the context of this implementation guide, will typically contain the following key data. 
    </p>

    <ul>
        <li>Metadata</li>
        <li>Specimen type</li>
            <ul>
                <li><strong>Nasopharyngeal:</strong> <a href="#specimen-type-nasopharyngeal">258500001</a></li>
                <li><strong>Oropharyngeal swab:</strong> <a href="#specimen-type-oropharyngeal-swab">461911000124106</a></li>
                <li><strong>Unknown:</strong> <a href="#specimen-type-unknown">119324002</a></li>
            </ul>
        <li>Specimen ID</li>
    </ul>

    <p class="heading">Process Lab Request</p>

    <p>
        Add text...
    </p>

    <h3>References</h3> <a name="references"> </a>

    <div>
        <ol>
            <li id="ref1">Post-COVID Conditions. (2022, December 16). Centers for Disease Control and Prevention. https://www.cdc.gov/coronavirus/2019-ncov/long-term-effects/index.html</li>
        </ol>
    </div>
</div>  